Hello, and welcome to Lesson 28 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，这里是 Wolfram U的微积分入门，第28课
The topic for this lesson is areas between curves.
本次课程的主题是  曲线间的面积
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the topic.
先简单回顾一下上节课
When you calculate an integral, you’re really finding the area
当你计算积分时 你实际上是在计算面积
between the curve of a function and the x axis.
由函数曲线和 x 所围成
For example, here’s a function,
比如 这个函数
and when you compute the integral for that function,
计算这个函数积分的时候
then what you’re really doing is to find the area under the curve.
实际上是在算曲线下的面积
In this case, it’s the area between –1 and 1,
这个例子中 区域在 -1 和 +1 之间
which are the limits for the integral over here.
-1 和 +1 是这个定积分的上下限
The question is what would happen
问题来了
if you want to find the area between two curves?
如何计算曲线之间的区域面积
This lesson will go over
这节课将会复习
several examples of how we can do this using Integrate.
几个如何使用 Integrate 的例子
Okay. Let’s take an example.
好 来看一个例子
Let’s say f[x] = 5 and g[x] = –x^2 + 1.
假设 f[x] = 5 和 g[x] = –x^2 + 1
Now clearly in this case, the function f
很清楚的 函数 f
is greater than the function g because that’s positive
比函数 g 高 因为 g 在这里是正的
and that’s going to be negative for most of the time,
而 g 大多时候是负的
but it won’t go over 1.
但是 g 不超过1
Now when you want to work out the area between them,
现在当你想算他们之间的面积的时候
what you do is look at the Riemann sums.
你要做的就是看黎曼和
Now in this case, the Riemann sums will have
这里 黎曼和是
a height equal to f minus g for each strip,
每个条带的高度等于 f 减 g
and the width will be (b – a)/n where b and a
宽度为 (b – a)/n 其中 b 和 b
are the limits of the integration interval.
是积分区域的上下限
Now the Riemann sum will be the sum of the heights times the widths,
现在黎曼和就是高度乘以宽度的总和
which is the same as the integral of f minus g.
与 f 减 g 的积分相同
Basically, if you want to find the area between the preceding curves,
基本上 如果要算前面的曲线之间的区域面积
then all you go is you work out the integral of f minus g,
要做的就是计算 f 减 g 的积分
and you get back the answer—76/3 in this case.
得到答案——在这种情况下为 76/3
Okay. Now two questions.
好的 现在有两个问题
First question: what would happen if
首先：如果
you didn’t know the limits of integration?
不知道积分的上下限呢？
Secondly, what would happen if you had to actually work out
其次 会怎么样 当你不得不去实际计算
which function, greater or less.
哪个函数大或小
But before that, let’s take a simple example.
但在此之前 看一个简单的例子。
Here are two functions, and you want to work out
这有两个函数 要算
the area between them with x = 1 on the left and x = 5 on the right.
这个区域在左端 x = 1 和右端 x = 5 之间
In this case, everything is given to you, so we can work out
这种情况下 一切条件都给你了 所以我们可以算出
the integral of f minus g and get the answer 88.
f 减 g 的积分 得到答案 88
Here is a plot of the area which we just computed.
这里是我们刚算的区域的图
Now back to the question which I asked earlier on.
现在回到先前提到的问题
First question: what happens if you’re not given any endpoints?
首先没有任何端点怎么办？
Let’s say you’ve got two functions, f and g,
假设有两个函数 f 和 g
and you want to find the area enclosed between the curves
想找到曲线之间的封闭区域
given by these functions.
由这俩函数确定
What you do then is you work out
要做的就是算
the points of intersection using Solve.
交点 用 Solve
The curves intersect at –√3 and √3.
曲线相交于 –√3 和 √3
Here is a plot of the curves between those limits,
这是在上下限之间的曲线的图
and you can see clearly that f is above g in all cases,
而且可以清楚地看到任何时候 f 都高于 g ，
so we can work out the integral of f minus g,
因此可以计算 f 减 g 的积分
and you get the answer with the area enclosed between these curves.
就得到了曲线间的面积
On the other hand, suppose you have the functions Sin[x] and Cos[x].
另一方面 假设有 Sin[x] 和 Cos[x]
You can see that the functions f and g are either
可以看到函数 f 和 g
above or below each other depending upon where you are.
彼此之间的高低关系取决你的位置
Let’s say you want to find the area between –3π/4 and 5π/4.
假设要找的区域在 –3π/4 和 5π/4 之间
That’s roughly starting over here and ending over there.
那大概是从这里开始 到那里结束
Initially, the cosine function is greater than the sine function,
开始 余弦函数大于正弦函数
and then the sine function is greater than the cosine
然后正弦大于余弦
for the rest of the interval.
在其余区间里
On the first interval, –3π/4 to 5π/4, you have g minus f
在第一个区间 –3π/4 到 5π/4 之间 有 g 减 f
because g is greater than f, and then you do the opposite
因为 g 比 f 大 然后做相反的事情
for the rest of the interval.
在其他区间里
Then you add the two answers, and you get back 4√2.
然后将两个答案相加 得到4√2
The point is you will now need to divide the integration
关键是现在需要划分区间
into two parts depending upon the behavior of f and g.
分为两个部分 具体取决于 f  和 g 的行为
Instead of doing that, what we do is we just call Integrate
若不这样做 我们只需调用 Integrate
with the absolute value function,
作用在绝对值函数上
which will take care of all the difficulties, and you get back
这将解决所有困难 然后得到
just the same answer from Integrate.
来自 Integrate 的相同答案。
Given two functions f and g,
给两个函数 f 和 g
if you do not know which one is greater or less,
如果不知道哪个更大或更小
then you use the absolute value function to find the area.
然后使用绝对值函数求面积
Okay. Let’s now talk about cases where you’ve got a function of y.
好的 现在 让我们谈谈 y 的函数的情况
So x is given as a function of y in these two functions, f and g.
现在 x 是 y 的函数在这两个函数 f 和 g
To find the area in this case, you now need y limits.
要找到这种情况下的区域，您现在需要 y 的限制
Again, you work with Riemann sums, but now you have
同样 使用黎曼和求和法 现在有
Riemann sums with widths given by Δy.
黎曼和的权由 Δy 给出
Instead of talking about upper and below,
与其说上下
we talk about rightmost and leftmost functions.
不如说最左边和最右边
In this case, if you plot the functions,
在这种情况下 如果绘制函数
it is clear that the function g is to the right of the function f,
很明显 函数 g 在函数 f 的右侧
so the area will be given by
所以面积是
the integral of g minus f between –5 and 5.
g 减去 f 在 –5 到 5 之间的积分
Okay. Now an example where you might actually need this is
好 现在 可能实际需要这个的示例是
let’s say you’re given y = 3x + 1 and the parabola y^2 = x + 4.
假设有 y = 3x + 1 和抛物线 y^2 = x + 4
In this case, y is not a function of x, so we try and write x
在这种情况下 y 不是 x 的函数 因此我们尝试将 x 写为
as a function of y by solving.
y 的函数
Set up two functions from the first solution over here
设两个函数 从第一个解中得到的
and the second solution over there.
和第二个解中得到的
Then you find out where they intersect.
然后找出它们的交点
Do a parametric plot, and it’s clear that
做一个参数图 很明显
you actually have the function f to the right of g.
实际上  在 g 的右侧具有函数 f
You do Integrate of f minus g between the limits (1 – √133)/6,
可以在上下限（1 –√133）/ 6 之间对 f 减 g 进行积分
et cetera, and you get back the answer
等一下 就会得到答案
for the area between those two curves.
这两条曲线之间的面积
You can either work with x limits or y limits.
可以使用 x 限制或 y 限制。
They both work just fine.
他们俩都很好
It’s now time to summarize the lesson.
现在该总结课程了
Basically, finding the area between curves
基本上，求曲线之间的区域面积
is really easy once you have integrals.
一旦有了积分 真的很容易
In case the function f is greater than the function g,
如果函数 f 大于 g
you simply do the integral of f minus g.
只需对 f 减去 g 进行积分
Now when you don’t have that information,
现在 当没有这些信息的时候
then what you do is you figure out
那你要做的就是弄清楚
where the functions intersect using Solve,
使用 Solve 解出相交的地方
figure out which function is above and which one is below,
找出哪个函数在上面 哪个在下面
and then you find the integral by doing
然后求得积分 通过做
the integral of f minus g or g minus f,
f 减 g 或者 g 减 f 的积分
or simply using the absolute value function.
或者只是使用绝对值函数
Of course if you’re given functions of y,
当然 如果给的是 y 的函数
then you work with y integrals,
然后对 y 积分
so let’s say you might do the integral of f minus g
因此 假设可以对 f 减 g 做积分
in a case where you know that f is to the right of g.
如果知道 f 在 g 的右侧
That brings me to the end of this lesson.
这次课到此为止
In the next lesson, we’ll talk about volume of solids.
在下一课中 我们将讨论固体体积
But before that, do review this topic of area between curves.
但是在此之前 请务必回顾一下曲线之间的面积这一主题
It’s a very important and useful part of calculus.
这是微积分中非常重要和有用的部分。
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
本节课到此为止，再见